[NARRATOR]
The end of the 19th century.
Amidst the upheaval caused
by the industrial revolution,
Britain steadily
expands its colonization.
Eventually its territories cover
one quarter of the earth--
an empire on which
the sun never sets.
Despite being the
greatest dominion in history,
the land is ruled
by the affluent,
which makes up less than three
percent of the total population.
In steep contrast with rapid
advancement of technology,
an archaic class structure
remains firmly rooted in place.
This system rigidly divides
people into social categories
where an individual's merit
is determined by the family
they're born into,
and as a result,
inevitably creates
widespread discrimination.
[WILLIAM] I take it
you're a gambling man?
Forgive the intrusion.
I couldn't help but notice
you studying the racing sheet.
Me? A gambler?
I'm a bit more of
a dabbler, really. My wife,
well, she's always telling me
if I have enough for the horses,
I should replace
the wallpaper first.
I see. Then perhaps I could
be of some assistance to you.
I may be able to
afford you the means
to acquire that new wallpaper
as well as a bouquet
of flowers for your wife.
If I didn't know better,
it sounds like you know
which horses will win.
Once you analyze the data,
you can predict the outcome.
It's exactly the same
as any other game.
[WILLIAM chuckles]
[LABOURER 2A] So then, what
about the upcoming Wessex Cup?
Which horse to bet on.
Might I suggest
the one who'll win it?
Right, like anybody could
know that ahead of time.
[WILLIAM]
John Striker's steed.
Huh?
[WILLIAM]
I said the horse belonging to
the trainer, John Striker,
will win the race.
Oh, yeah? And you're certain?
Nothing in life is certain,
but the odds are favourable.
You know,
somehow this kid also predicted
the winners of the last race.
Tell me, lad, you able
to see into the future?
No, sir, but horse racing
is like any other game.
By studying the figures, you
can win 80 percent of the time.
[WILLIAM chuckles]
[GROUP grunts]
[LABOURER 2B]
"Studying the figures," he says.
Can you really predict
winners by tallying numbers?
[LABOURER 2C]
Search me.
Well... he is upper
crust, after all.
Boy's got that fancy learning,
not like us commoners.
[ROADSIDE MERCHANT 2A]
Young master!
Uh?
I'm sorry,
but I need your advice.
It's the flowers I sell.
When I keep them at home,
they wither up.
I would suggest adding
just a splash of vinegar
to whichever pail
you use to water them.
Oh! Some vinegar?
And that'll keep
them looking fresh?
Yes... but only a little bit.
[BAKER 2A]
There he is!
I wanted to thank you
for all your help!
I set out some strychnine,
just like you said,
and the rats, poof,
completely disappeared.
For you. A token of my thanks.
You're too kind.
I gladly accept.
[WILLIAM]
Brother.
Out and about town, I see.
Indeed. I'd business
to attend to.
But headed home.
Do you care to join me?
[WILLIAM]
Sure.
A smartly dressed lad like that,
you'd think I'd
know who they were.
Those are the sons
of the Moriarty family.
[OLD WOMAN 2A grunts]
[BAKER 2A] On the left is
the oldest, Mister Albert,
and the other is Master William.
It's strange.
That younger brother,
I could've sworn he looked
different than that before.
[ALBERT] You seem to
be as popular as ever.
So what sort of advice
were they in need of this time?
Just a few simple matters
pertaining to
horticulture and gambling.
You've become quite the
consultant to the townspeople
regardless of their predicament.
Continue building
that mind palace
until it becomes
a wonder of the world.
And a benefit to all the people.
Thank you.
I am endeavouring to do so.
[WILLIAM]
I nearly forgot.
A gift from the baker whom
I advised the other day
on how to deal with
his mouse problems.
[ALBERT]
Then I suppose you could
call them your "just desserts."
You really ought to
share them with Louis.
I won't breathe
a word of it to anyone.
That's very kind of you.
[ALBERT] No. If my parents find
out, there'll be hell to pay.
It seems like we're
partners in crime.
[WILLIAM chuckles]
Uh! Louis!
Welcome back home, brother.
[coughs]
[WILLIAM]
What are you doing?
You should still be in bed.
[SIMON]
The boy's limbs work.
So, I don't see why
he can't be of use.
But never mind him.
Who gave you permission to
ride in the family carriage?
[ALBERT]
I did.
[SIMON]
Mister Albert!
Welcome back home, sir--
I let him ride along
in the carriage.
Are you satisfied?
There's no denying you have
a generous heart, Mister Albert.
But you need to maintain
an appropriate distance
from these two,
or I'll be reprimanded
by her ladyship.
Louis, Hide these.
[LOUIS]
Right.
Remove that coat immediately.
You may be cloaked in
Mister Albert's hand-me-downs,
but they're still wasted
on the likes of you.
[SIMON] You dare dress
yourself in such costly attire
and stroll around town?
One could scarcely
believe not so long ago,
you were living on the streets,
begging for scraps.
To think, now I'm serving two
brats pulled from the gutter,
lower than myself.
There's no greater shame.
[ALBERT]
Simon! You speak too freely.
[SIMON] But, Mister Albert,
these waifs are--
[WILLIAM]
What's all the commotion?
Accept my apologies.
[SIMON]
Master William.
Going out? Where to?
The school. You are aware
that's where I volunteer.
Even if you are
doing it for charity,
I still think you've got one
morbid sense of curiosity.
It's beyond me why you would
choose to surround yourself
with the disgusting
lower classes.
[WILLIAM] It goes against
the very principles
of being a noble. We do
everything we can to avoid them.
Yet you run to
meet their embrace.
Remember that cold
you had last week?
I bet I know where
you caught it from.
[ALBERT]
I hate it. Everything.
This whole world.
Our nation, and its
cursed caste system.
A mark placed upon
the soul at birth.
It's sickening.
[ALBERT] I beg you,
forgive my absence last week,
but it seems I caught
a bit of a cold.
[TEACHER 2A] There's nothing
to forgive, Lord Moriarty.
Your visits are the highpoint
for the children and
brighten their day.
But frankly, shouldn't
you be back at home
resting and building
up your strength?
I would, but it hardly
feels like home these days.
Oh?
[GIRL 2A] There you are!
Can you read this book to us?
Of course. I'll be right there--
[GIRL 2A giggles]
Here! This is the book Mister
Moriarty gave us to read.
[ALBERT]
Those two boys.
I don't think
I've seen them before.
Ah, yes.
We took the brothers in just
last week while you were away.
The younger one is so sickly
and frail, the poor thing.
That aside, both are literate
and even know Latin.
Moreover, the older boy
is knowledgeable
in a wide range of subjects,
specifically maths
and chemistry.
Whenever he opens his mouth,
he leaves adults speechless.
Before their arrival here, I
understand they would venture to
the British Museum's
reading room unattended.
Oddly enough,
the head librarian asked
if we could take charge of them.
[ALBERT]
An orphan
with the intellect to leave
even adults speechless.
Initially, I simply regarded him
as some sort of prodigy.
That was all.
Nothing else
triggered my interest.
But that soon changed.
Are you seriously
fostering an orphan?
Yes! Don't you think
it's simply wonderful?
By doing so,
we're saving some poor child
from a fate they had
absolutely no control over.
How kind of you.
[VISCOUNT 2A clears throat]
I'm deeply moved, Your Grace.
Not only by your
humanitarian views,
but by the fact that you
put action behind them.
Then you'll--
Arrangements will be made
to welcome an orphan
into my home
and raise them like
they were my own.
Sir! I just knew you had
a kind and charitable heart.
[EARL MORIARTY grumbles]
[MADAME PÉNIÈRES]
Lord Moriarty.
May I count on you to
open up your heart as well?
Uh, of course.
[COUNTESS MORIARTY]
Are you mad?
What do you mean,
we're taking in an orphan?
My word is final.
There's no point in us arguing.
And my word?
Our family already has
two outstanding sons.
Is that not good enough for you?
What's worse,
it'll be an orphan from
God only knows where!
The nobility have
certain obligations,
including acts of charity.
You should know this!
Huh? It's the Duchess
Pénières, isn't it?
The woman's obsessed
with helping the poor.
She put you up
to this! Didn't she?!
Give her this message:
we decline!
Either you tell her, or I will!
[EARL MORIARTY]
Don't be a fool? I couldn't!
The shame of going
back on my word.
[COUNTESS MORIARTY]
You must!
[ALBERT]
They bloomed magnificently.
Oh, yes.
But only because I took that
young man's gardening advice.
I'm not sure if he read it
in a book somewhere,
but regardless, the range of
subjects he knows is astounding.
So do you think that you could
teach us how to do maths?
If you know your maths,
you can make loads of money
in the city with a real job.
No way! He was supposed to read
from the next
chapter of our book!
[BOY 2B] Never mind all
that school rubbish!
Tell us how to win at chess!
Children, really.
You can't expect him to
fulfill all of your requests.
But what about you, Teacher?
You asked him to make
some cough medicine and
he knew everything about it!
But that's different.
[ALL laughing]
[ALBERT] You want me to select
an orphan to be our ward?
Are you sure?
[EARL MORIARTY]
You heard me.
Since you regularly
volunteer at that school,
you know their stock.
Go and find us
a suitable candidate.
Preferably one
that's well behaved
and won't cause us any trouble.
Yes, Father.
Uh?
[WILLIAM] According
to these calculations,
one person can advance at a rate
of roughly ten inches per hour.
Taking into account
the firmness of the soil,
in order to dig
a distance of 40 yards
it would require
a week of labour.
[ALBERT]
Sounds rather complicated to me.
[WILLIAM]
Lord Moriarty.
[MEN grumble]
[WORKMAN 2D]
What do ya say, fellas?
I guess we'd better get
back to our work then, huh?
[WORKMAN 2B]
If we don't get a move on,
we'll never finish today.
I hope I wasn't interrupting.
No. Anyway, we finished
the most important part.
You're like an advisor
for the townspeople.
Actually, more of a
consultant, I would say.
The truth is this is
how I've gotten by.
When I help others, they give
me food or money in gratitude.
It's a more peaceful way of
living as opposed to stealing.
Anyway, if I come across
someone in a dire situation,
and I'm able to help them,
then I like to do
whatever I can for them.
Did you hear the news?
Someone managed to sneak into
Old Mister Thompson's strongbox.
[MAN 2B]
Yeah, I did.
Apparently, they made off with
all the valuables in his cellar.
So, some thief stole the money
he extorted from the poor.
It serves him right.
Still though,
the bloke who did it
must be something else.
[MAN 2C]
I mean, digging a side tunnel
from the sewer to sneak in.
[MAN 2B]
Got that right.
No small feat,
tunnelling for 40 yards.
[ALBERT gasps]
No small feat,
tunnelling for 40 yards.
[WILLIAM] In order to dig
a distance of forty yards,
it would require
a week of labour.
[ALBERT] Impossible.
It's only my imagination.
Welcome. Lord Moriarty,
how lovely to see you again.
Is something the matter?
Your complexion is
rather pale today.
I-- No, I'm fine.
You can find all the children
assembled in the chapel.
[BOTH]
Hm?
[GIRL 2A] Then, the nobility
are good people, right?
[WILLIAM] Very true. Every day,
they wear the finest clothes,
eat delicious food, and fall
asleep in their warm beds.
That's on account
of their forefathers
and their contributions
to this great land.
The upper-class are important.
[GIRL 2A]
Mm-hm.
Perhaps, but they're
not all good.
They sneer down at me
from their carriages.
Treat me like rubbish.
My poor mother.
She worked for a rich man
and he put her through hell.
She ended up dying
because of it.
You're right. They are human,
and can be corrupted.
[WILLIAM] So then, what happens
when a bad nobleman shows up?
Well? Remember what
I told you before?
We fight 'em!
[ALBERT gasps]
[CHILDREN]
We fight and kill 'em all!
Fight the rich! Kill the rich!
Bring death to
every rotten noble!
Fight the rich! Kill the rich!
Bring death to
every rotten noble!
Fight the rich! Kill the rich!
Bring death to
every rotten noble!
[ALBERT] All we have to do
to make this country perfect
is to rid it of villainy.
Under God's watchful eye
he sat there,
preaching the ways of evil
in order to make the world just.
[ALBERT gasps]
Oh. I'm terribly sorry!
[gasps]
[MAID 2A cries]
[WILLIAM]
You're back home early, Brother.
What have you done?
[WILLIAM]
Nothing of consequence.
Just disciplining
a careless servant.
I swear, these people...
They bring it upon
themselves, you know.
They can't even make a cup
of tea without screwing up.
Suppose I'll have
to talk to Father
and have her put
back on the streets.
[ALBERT growls]
[ALBERT] You're like an
advisor for the townspeople.
Actually, more of a
consultant, I would say.
[WILLIAM] The truth is,
this is how I've gotten by.
When I help others, they give me
food or money in gratitude.
I swear, these people,..
They bring it upon
themselves, you know.
We fight 'em!
[CHILDREN]
We fight and kill 'em all!
Bring death to
every rotten noble!
[ALBERT gasps]
[WILLIAM] If I come across
someone in a dire situation,
and I'm able to help them,
then I like to do
whatever I can for them.
[ALBERT gasps]
So you wanted to speak with me?
Death to every rotten noble.
You overheard that, did you?
I found it to be an
outstanding lecture.
Still, making an enemy
of the nobility
means picking a quarrel
with the whole country.
Can you fight them?
The entire system?
[WILLIAM chuckles]
That's the idea.
[WILLIAM] Our lives should
be seen as equal in value.
We all deserve the
right to happiness.
But in this country,
that possibility doesn't exist.
It's a luxury only
the rich can afford.
This class system is
a curse on civilization.
It causes people's hearts to
become poisoned and twisted.
As a result,
it gives rise to devils.
Therefore, the opposite
must also be true.
Once the demon is exorcised,
the heart can become pure
and the curse, lifted.
Mark my words,
this country will be purified.
[WILLIAM] Are you going to
report me to Scotland Yard?
[ALBERT gasps]
[WILLIAM] As a nobleman,
I bet you'd like that--
to see me taken
away in shackles.
[ALBERT]
An orphan,
with the intellect to leave
even adults speechless.
Initially, I simply regarded
him as some sort of prodigy.
That was all.
Nothing else triggered
my interest.
But that soon changed.
Look! There're survivors!
Doctor! Quickly!
[FIREMAN 2A]
Are you all right?
My name is Albert.
Albert James Moriarty.
And these two...
[ALBERT] Next time
on Moriarty the Patriot  .
"The Scarlet Eyes Act Two."